

Victor Fernando Lopes de Souza

Engineering Student at CentraleSupélec



8 July 1999, Brazilian



+33 0665923179



victor flosouza@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/victorflosouza



github.com/victorsouza89

About Me ——

Passionate for innovation and technology. Interested in approaching complex problems and grasping complex concepts.

Looking for a final year internship starting in May 2023.

Enthusiast of Mathematics, System Modeling, Control Systems and Discrete Automation.

Skills —

Good Mathematical Background and knowledge in Control's Systems, Automata and Discrete-Event's Systems.

Multiple experiences on Python, LETEX, Matlab, Simulink, Linux, Git, R, Ladder, Java, C++, AutoIt and BASIC.

Experience on data analysis and neural nets using Pandas, Numpy, Tensforflow and Keras.

Experience on Web developing using PHP, HTML, CSS, SQL and JavaScript.

Languages: Portuguese (mother tongue), English, French and Spanish.

Education

2022-2023	Université Paris-Saclay Master in Systems, Signals and Image Processing	Gif-Sur-Yvette (FR)
2021-2023	CentraleSupélec Engineering, with mention in Control	Gif-Sur-Yvette (FR)
2018-2023	UFSC - Universidade Federal de Santa Catarina Control and Automation Engineering PAM - Advanced Mathematics Program	Florianópolis (BR)
2021-2022	Paris IV - Sorbonne Université Bachelor's degree in Philosophy	Paris (FR)
2014-2017	IFSC - Instituto Federal de Santa Catarina Engineering Technician in Electronics	Florianópolis (BR)

Work Experience

2020-2021	at EMBRAPII, in partnership with Central Energia (R& Worked on building, training, and evaluating LSTM n ing the prediction of precipitation data for energy training.	etworks regard-
2018-2021	Student Researcher in Algebraic Topology Florianópolis (BR) at IMPA (Brazilian Institute of Pure and Applied Mathematics) Research on advanced topics related to Geometric Group Theory	
2018–2019	Calculus Teaching Assistant at the Mathematics Department, UFSC Developed PHP, Shell, BASIC and Kernel scripts to related to the management, monitoring and control of	
2016–2017	Intern as Web Developer at Oi S.A. (third largest telecommunication company is Developed PHP, Shell, BASIC and Kernel scripts to related to the management, monitoring and control of	automate tasks

Projects

2022	Training Neural Networks with Kalman Filters Gif-Sur-Yvette (FR) Implementation of modern control methods for training Neural Nets and use of the Kalman filter as an optimization algorithm
2022	Exploring portfolio optimization methods, with BNP Gif-Sur-Yvette (FR) Construction, Implementation and Evaluation of different portfolio allocation methods
2022	System for inform on cancer, with Health Guide AI Gif-Sur-Yvette (FR) Testing of different recommendation algorithms for this purpose
2021-2022	Neural Nets: Attacks and Robustness, with SystemX Gif-Sur-Yvette (FR) Study and implementation of some attack methods on NN systems

Honours and Awards

2021 BRAFITEC, Merit Scholarship for Double Degree in Fi	rance
2019 Qualified to Final Phase, OBMU (National University I	Maths Olympiad)
2018 Freshman Award, OEI (Organization of Ibero-Americ	an States)
2017 Silver Medal, OBMEP (National High School Mathema	atics Olympiad)
2016 Silver Medal, OBMEP (National High School Mathema	atics Olympiad)
2014 Honourable Mention, OBMEP (National High School I	Maths Olympiad)